

# Stephen A Thomas Front End Web Development

**▼** stephen@sathomas.me

+1 (404) 457-8652

http://jsDataV.is

http://sathomas.me

O github.com/sathomas

## **About Me**

Front end architect with extensive experience in modern web development and a passion for delivering exceptional user experiences. Grounded in the ethnographic foundations of usability and human computer interaction with a deep understanding of front end development based on the principles of accessibility, progressive enhancement and responsive design. Introduced and tutored development teams in the adoption of leading front end technologies such as MV• frameworks and test-driven development. Work experience includes corporate enterprises and service providers, as well as charitable support of non-profit organizations including the Centers for Disease Control and the World Health Organization.

## Skills & Areas of Expertise

JavaScript	• • • • •
Backbone.js	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\circ$
jQuery	• • • • •
REST	• • • • 0
HTML5	• • • • •
CSS3	• • • • •
Responsive Design	• • • • •
Progressive Enhancement	• • • • •
Accessibility	• • • • •

Test Driven Development

## **Work Experience**

Application Developer at Georgia Tech 2013 - Present

Web developer in Office of Education Technology focussed on large-scale web platforms for academic research and collaboration.

Front End Architect at Dell SecureWorks 2007 - 2013

Responsible for all aspects of front end design and development for web and mobile applications.

Chief Architect at Wave 7 Optics 2001 - 2006

Led design and development of IP-based optical network architecture for the delivery of video, voice and data services in business and residential applications.

Chief Technical Officer at TransNexus 1997 - 2001

Led technical development for startup company creating financial clearinghouse for Internet-based communication services.

## **Publications**

Data Visualization with JavaScript. No Starch: San Francisco, 2015.

"Simple Responsive Images With CSS Background Images." published 22 July 2013 on *Smashing Magazine*.

"Unit Testing Backbone.js Applications." published 25 February 2013 on *JSPRO.com*.

"Web-Based Visualization." published 5 November 2012 on *UICloud*.

HTTP Essentials: Protocols for Secure, Scaleable Web Sites. John Wiley & Sons: New York, 2001.

SSL & TLS Essentials: Securing the Web. John Wiley & Sons: New York, 2000.

#### **Education**

Master of Science from School of Electrical Engineering. Georgia Institute of Technology. Atlanta, Georgia. 1994. GPA: 4.0 (A=4).